Luca Lanziani

Curriculum Vitae

83 Crampton Street London, UK SE17 3BU ⊠ luca@lanziani.com github.com/Nss ' lanziani.com



Summary

I achieved my master degree in Computer Engineering in 2010, from these studies I learned how to approach problems academically but I never forget to use a pinch of creativity. I'm an open source addict, I love to share knowledge and I will never get tired of learning new things.

Latest experience: Betting platform (Python/Javascript), sync and backup multi-platform client (Python/Javascript), HTML5 platform (HTML5/Javascript), a plugin system and communication bus on Linux Embedded (C/Libdl/pubsub).

Experience

2013–Present **Software Engineer**, SMARKETS, London.

Smarkets is a betting exchange for trading sports, politics and entertainment events. I'm currently working with **Python**/Flask, **Javascript** and devops tasks. This experience is giving me the possibility to work in a complete production environment, using various technologies such as Vagrant, Jenkins, Chef, RabbitMQ and practices as Scrum and CI.

2012–2013 **Software Engineer**, FILEROCK, Rome.

FileRock is a secure, backup and synchronization service. I mainly worked on the client, a multi-platform software that encrypts and syncs data in the cloud completely written in **Python** and on a responsive web interface using **Angularjs** and PhoneGap to bring it on mobile devices.

2011–2012 **Software Engineer / CoDreamer**, GRAPILY, Rome.

Grapily was a web platform to generate HTML5 applications simply composing of a HTML5 interface and a services API. This experience gave me a good knowledge of HTML5, **Javascript** (Backbone, AngularJS), **NodeJS**, startups, team building.

2011–2011 **Software Engineer**, ROMA TRE UNIVERSITY, Rome.

I designed and developed a software framework in ${\bf C}$ language on a Linux embedded platform (FOX Board G20), for the SAETTA project. The framework takes care of dynamically-load software modules and manage the communication between them. From this experience I learned how to write multi-thread software and how to handle concurrency.

Education

2010 Masters of Computer Engineering, Roma Tre University, Rome.

2007 Bachelor of Computer Engineering, Roma Tre University, Rome.

Skills (sorted by experience)

OS Linux, OSX, Windows

Languages Python, Javascript, C, Ruby, Java, Erlang, Ocaml, Pascal

Frameworks Nodejs, Angularjs, Backbonejs, Flask, RoR

Tools Chef, Vagrant, Jenkins, RabbitMQ

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL

Languages

Italian Mothertongue

English Intermediate

Professional working proficiency